# SOFÍA IGNACIA ZAMBRANO MERICQ

Software Engineering Student
Pontifical Catholic University of Chile
<a href="https://sofizambrano.github.io/">https://sofizambrano.github.io/</a>
+569 9020 5020 / sofi.zambrano@gmail.com

### SUMMARY

Web and mobile developer specialized in front-end development. I consider myself very passionate for GUI design and I look forward to keep learning skills to improve in it. I love practicing advanced choreographic steps, teaching math, solving Sudoku puzzles, taking pictures and travelling. I am proactive, organized, empathic, creative, good at handicrafts and artistic work.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

Mar 2017 – Jul 2017	educarchile: iOS mobile application developer I experienced what is like to work with a real client and having intensive team work. I learned how to build a native mobile application for iOS using Swift. My work focused on requirement analysis, graphical interfaces design and dealing with constraints.
Aug 2016 – Dec 2016	Pontifical Catholic University of Chile: Software Engineering teaching assistant Experience as a product owner of other students, taught good practices for coding in Ruby on Rails.
Mar 2016 – Jul 2016	<b>Software Engineering Class Project:</b> Ruby on Rails web application developer I learned how to build a web application using Ruby on Rails framework. The application purpose was to offer an online free book library, where users could search, classify with tags, read, convert and share books.
Mar 2016 – Jul 2016	<b>Databases Class Project:</b> PHP web application developer I learned PHP interactions with a PostgreSQL database for developing a simple web social network integrated with a site for searching movies.
Aug 2016 – Dec 2016 Aug 2014 – Dec 2014	Pontifical Catholic University of Chile: Introduction to Programming teaching assistant I taught Python language in laboratory sessions for first and second year students motivating and guiding them to solve programming challenges.
Aug 2017 - present Mar 2017 – Jul 2017 Aug 2016 – Dec 2016	Pontifical Catholic University of Chile: other teaching assistant experiences Information Technology Project Management Computer Architecture Information Systems

## **SKILLS**

Programming languages: Python, Ruby, Swift, PHP, HTML, CSS SQL database queries, deployment with Heroku platform and version control with GitHub repositories.

Languages: Spanish native speaker, English fluent speaker (ETS TOEIC Exam 905/990 points; IELTS Academic Exam 7.0 overall band score) and basic Pinyin (Chinese). Instruments: piano and flute

# **EDUCATION**

Mar 2012 – Jul 2018	Pontifical Catholic University of Chile, Santiago, Chile
	<ul> <li>Software Engineering</li> </ul>
Nov 2009 – Feb 2010	Episcopal High School of Jacksonville, Jacksonville, FL, USA
Jul 1998 – Dec 2011	Dunalastair School, Santiago, Chile